Frédéric Dubouchet

frederic.dubouchet@gmail.com | +41 79 104 85 76

RESUME OBJECTIVE

Senior software engineer and team manager in the computer engineering sector for more than 20 years, including at some of the biggest companies (Nagra, CERN, Google), the experience I have accumulated can provide solutions in embedded, big data, microservices, and machine learning. In addition, I have been teaching C++ at the bachelor and master level for about two years and find it enjoyable. With my experience and contacts, I can be a valuable addition to your company.

EDUCATION

HES-SO // MASTER

MSE IN INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES

2011 - 2013 | Lausanne, CH Thesis: (6/6) - Betatron tune measurement with the LHC damper using a GPU

HES-SO // BASHELOR

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2002 - 2005 | Geneva, CH Thesis: (5.5 / 6) - 3D stereoscopy

EPFL

COMPUTER SCIENCE

1997 - 1999 | Lausanne, CH Unfinished - Founded Eleaf Sarl

MATURITÉ

TYPE S. SCIENTIFIQUE

1997 | Geneva, CH

Grad. (74 / 90) - Swiss secondary school degree

LINKS

Github:// anirul

LinkedIn:// Frédéric Dubouchet

COURSEWORK

MASTER

Artificial Intelligence + Practicum Cryptography

Software Security
Optimizations

Fourrier and Wavelets

Web Data Mining

GPU computing

Cloud computing

BASHELOR

Digital Signal Processing Compilers + Practicum Theory of Computation Operating Systems Databases Virtual Machine + Practicum Computer Graphics + Practicum

EXPERIENCE

LOGITECH | PRINCIPAL REAL-TIME GRAPHIC ENGINEER

May 2022 - April 2023 | Lausanne, CH

Produce a 3D stereoscopic view of a person from 3D point cloud (using OpenGL/Vulkan)

- Advice on 3D GPU and visualization (CUDA/OpenGL/Vulkan)
- Implementation of a software (C++/OpenGL/Vulkan)

CONTRACT WORK | Senior Software Engineer

July 2020 - February 2021 | Sion, CH

Work in the domain of (AI/ML), 3D graphics, and networks

- Toolset for Unreal Engine 4 (C++)
- Implementation of network protocol (C#/nat-pmp)
- Distributed computing and capturing hardware (C++/gRPC)

ORIGINAL SCORE | FOUNDER

March 2019 - Now | Sion, CH

Create a game to release on Steam

- Negotiation with editors, contractors and financial sector
- Managing a team of contractors, graphists and game designers

GOOGLE | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

October 2015 - February 2019 | Zürich, CH

Working on Google Shopping from anti-spam to database

- Database writing for the Google Shopping group (C++/OpenCV/gRPC)
- Reviewing process for online automatic purchase (C++/Javascript/Java)
- Version checking system from online automatic purchase (C++/git/gRPC)

IDIAP RESEARCH INSTITUT | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

August 2014 - August 2015 | Martigny, CH

Developer for research projects

- Teaching computer vision to researchers (C++/OpenCL/OpenCV)
- Robotic and computer vision projects (C++/OpenCL/CUDA/OpenCV)
- Automatic Speech Recognition (Python)

CERN | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2006 - December 2013 | Geneva, CH

Software and drivers for controlling custom hardware board in a realtime environment, on LynxOS and then Linux

- Leader for the Linac4 RF control system, management of a team (C++)
- LHC RF Beam control: architecture, coordination, implementation (C++)
- ADT damper: architecture, coordination, implementation (C++/OpenCL)

NAGRAVISION | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2000 - 2002 | Lausanne, CH

Content management and encryptions for digital television

- Porting the software from Win32 to Linux and TRU64 UNIX (C/C++)
- Multiplexer driver for digital television (C)

TFACHING

SAE | Creative Media Education

September 2020 - August 2021 | Geneva, CH

- Beginner lecture (C++)
- How to implement a basic physic engine (C++)
- Computer Graphics (OpenGL/C++)
- Optimization (C++/OpenCL/CUDA/Assembly)

EPAC | École Professionnelle des Arts Contemporains

September 2019 - July 2020 | Saxon, CH

- 3D infographics and game technologies (C++/OpenGL/gRPC/Socket/...)
- Handling of Unreal 4 (C++/Blueprint)

SAE | Creative Media Education

February 2019 - Now | once per month | Geneva, CH

- Game Engine technologies (C++/Socket/...)
- Handling of Unreal 4 (C++/Blueprint)

SGA | Swiss Game Academy

August 2016 | July 2019 | Fribourg, CH

• Handling of Unreal 4 (Blueprint)

RESEARCH

CERN | GRADUATE RESEARCH

July 2013 - December 2013 | Geneva, CH

Betatron tune measurement with the LHC damper using a GPU with Prof. Paul Albuquerque and Dr. Wolfgang Höfle during my master thesis. A system to make real-time Fourier transform on GPU to better react to instabilities in the LHC beam using the ADT damper. It was on display at the IBIC 2013 conference in Oxford, UK.

HEPIA | Undergraduate Research

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013 | Geneva, CH

I made a simple comparison of OpenCL and CUDA performances for the Hepia. Implementation of various algorithms using OpenCL, available on GitHub.

SKILLS

LANGUAGE | NATURAL

French C2 Mother tongue

English B2 Fluent German В1 Rusted Japanese A1 Beginner

TECHNICAL | LANGUAGES

- Over 100'000 lines
 - (++
 - (
- Over 10'000 lines
 - C#
 - Java
 - JavaScript
 - Json
- Over 1'000 lines
 - Assembly
 - ATEX
 - Lua
 - Python
 - XML/XSD

TECHNICAL | Frameworks

- cmake
- FreeBSD
- git
- gRPC
- Linux
- macOS
- PostgreSQL
- Protocol Buffers
- Unreal Engine 4/5
- VCPKG
- Windows

AWARDS AND PROJECTS

2001	Ping	32k game	C++,RayTracing	6 th at Mekka and Symposium
2002	El Loco Megabus	32k game	C++,OpenGL	1 st at Mekka and Symposium
2005	panoptriptikum	intro 4k	8Bit-Script	2 nd at Breakpoint
2006	Biolite	96k game	C++,DirectX	6 th at Breakpoint
2009	miniDHT	network	C++,protobuf	Distributed Hash Table (P2P)
2010	Biolite Reloaded	game	C++,Irrlicht	1 st at Buenzli
2012	MOLA Parser	research	C++	Parsing of NASA Mars Orbital Laser Altimetry
2014	See Mark	game	C++,Irrlicht	Epic Game Jam
2015	CPPS UE4	research	Blueprint	Multiscreen setup for use in an earthquake simulator
2015	Mirages	game	Blueprint	Global Game Jam
2015	Meow Zedong,	game	Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2016	Green Revenge	game	Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2017	Maneki Neko,	game	Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2018	Isotops	game	C++,Blueprint	Nordic Game Jam
2018	Meow Zedong 2,	game	C++,Blueprint	Epic Game Jam
2019	Mini Epic City Builder	game	C++	Epic Game Jam
2020	Frame	engine	C++,OpenGL	3D Engine (Bloom, PBR, SSAO, Deferred Rendering,)
2022	Unreal Mine Sweeper Plugin	demo	C++	Mine sweeper as a plugin for Unreal 4.